#### **RESUME**

Name : Riya Kuriakose

**E-Mail ID** : riyakuriakose29@gmail.com

**Mobile No.** : 9689680769

#### **ASPIRATION**

To reach heights by applying my skills and abilities, to work with dedication in fulfilling my organizations and my own goals. Gain immense personal and professional experiences andthereby contribute towards my family and society and to grow myself as a person.

# ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Level	Stream	Institute	Board/University	Year of Passing	Percentage
МВА	Finance	Pratibha Institute of Business Management	Pune University	2015	67.57%
B.COM	Commerce	M. U. College of Commerce	Pune University	2013	63.16%
H.S.C	Commerce	Jai Hind Jr. College	Maharashtra Board	2010	68.00%
S.S.C.	General	Jai Hind High School	Maharashtra Board	2008	69.23%

## **SKILLS**

- Advanced Knowledge of MS Office, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Outlook.
- SAP
- Application& Reporting Knowledge on PeopleSoft, Business Object,
  3DExperience.
- Kyriba.
- Workday.
- Basic Knowledge of VBA Automation.
- Strong Communication skills.
- Strong analytical skills.

- Problem Solver.
- Strong decision-making skills.
- Tally.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- Certificate course in Soft skills Diploma.
- Certificate course in Soft skills Advance Diploma.
- Certificate of Merit in cyber awareness (Autonomous Course).
- Certificate course in Event Management.
- Certificate course in Insurance.
- Certificate of Participation in the seminar on Non-Government Organizations (NGO's).
- Certificate of Participation in the seminar on Leadership and Employee Engagement.
- Certificate of Merit for the completion of N.S.S for a period of two years and has alsoattended a Special Camp under the National Service Scheme of Govt. of India.
- Certificate for having painted for UNICEF Fund.
- Certificate of Merit for All-India Camel Color Contest 2001.
- Pre-Senior UN Information Passed Certificate for the 49th Annual All India UNInformation Test and secured 46% marks.
- Passed Certificate for All India National Environment Talent Search Examination (NETSE)and secured 36% marks.

#### PROJECT UNDERTAKEN

- Worked for 4 months and completed summer internship project in "Deepak Fertilizers and Petrochemicals Pvt Ltd" under topic "A detail study of export procedures and documentation" in SAP.
- Six sigma yellow belt "Unidentified and unapplied cash in DS India".

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Johnson Matthey Chemicals India Pvt Ltd MIDC, Mumbai

**Finance Executive** 

**Duration: December 2022 – January 2023** 

- Debtors reconciliation from time to time.
- Credit Evaluation and Releasing of credit blocks.
- Tracking payments to internal and external stakeholders.
- Ensure timely bank payments, excise duty payments, vendor and employee payments.
- Compute taxes and prepare tax returns.
- Reconcilialtion of accounts payable and receivable.
- Maintaining the billing system.
- Generating invoices and account statements.
- Bad debts calculation.
- Handling completion of statutory & tax audit within stipulated time.
- Performing weekly payment run on every Monday and Thursday.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Dassault Systemes Solutions Pvt Ltd (A 3DPLM Software Company), Hinjewadi, Pune

#### **Billing & Revenue Accounting Specialist:**

**Duration: March 2016 – August 2022** 

- Responsible for Accounts Receivable Cash Application for EMEA (Velizy), ASIA (Malaysia), NAM (Waltham) & Solidworks regions.
- Preparing Credit Collection Dashboards for top 10 overdue customers. This report was directly sent to Worldwide Shared Service Centers. Based on which the directors provide overview and take decisions for future collections.
- Was responsible to apply cash for payments received against correct invoices in cashapplication process for all regions.
- Was responsible for manual creation of invoices and credit notes.
- Was responsible for completion of all adhoc request from customers.
- Was responsible for sending all invoices raised to customers through their portals or through mails.
- Was responsible for collection of withholding and TDS certificates from customers.
- Was responsible for reconciliations of withholding tax certificates with AR postings.
- Was responsible to provide all files and reportings to auditors as per their request with backups.
- Was responsible to have calls with auditors to clear their doubts and queries and also explain them the end to end process.
- Was responsible to handle all exceptions while performing cash application i.e. AR transfers, write offs, TDS, withholding tax, bank charges/fees, AR

returns, wrong BU transfers, AP returns, payroll, treasury funds, hedge payments, royalty payments, discount payments, FX variance, cross currencies, credit card payments, cheque payments, advance payments, partial payments etc.

- Responsible for applying anti-piracy payments.
- Responsible for applying market place i.e stripe payments.
- Responsible for booking all unidentified cash into clearing account.
  Providing analysis on funds kept in clearing account on monthly basis.
- Prepare and provide AR aging report to all collectors on weekly basis to check on collections.
- Was responsible to set-up weekly calls with collectors and customers for discussion on various queries, receivables and expected date of payments.
- Provide weekly analysis on ON Account (OA File) to collectors.
- Major contribution showed in DS Indian BU's. Was directly reporting to Chief FinancialOfficer (CFO).
- Was responsible to provide balance confirmations to customers on monthly basis on company letter head with stamped and signed by CFO. This was to ensure that the outstanding balance as per AR books and customers books are matching.
- Was responsible in taking calls with CFO for discussion on late payments, OA payments and overdue payments.
- Was responsible in taking all calls with customers for reconciliations of their books and our books so that the outstanding balances match to avoid or correct any wrong bookings done.
- Was responsible to prepare AR reporting and post and reconcile AR activity to GeneralLedger at month end & quarter end closing.
- Responsible for bank reconciliations. Checking all GL postings done and finding out any entries stuck or unapplied cash.
- Providing analysis on non posting of GL entries after bank recon.
- Taking follow-ups with bank and treasury team for the payments that is to be received.
- Was responsible to directly provide all monthly and quarterly reporting's to CFO.
- Worked on DSO Calculations and also provided analysis on manual calculation of DSO.
- Worked on TDS & GST deductions for Indian regions.
- Was responsible to book all the TDS on GST tax for government customers.
- Was responsible to collect the certificates or prove from customers for all the TDS on GST bookings and later reconcile it with tax team.
- Was responsible to provide all TDS postings done by AR team to tax team in order to file the tax returns.
- Good organizational and problem solving skills.

- Maintained 100% accuracy throughout the entire career with zero escalations.
- Worked with stringent deadlines.
- Managed team of 25 people.
- Trained all the new joiners in team.
- Maintaining autonomy rule in process.
- Was responsible for conducting team meetings and trainings for any management updates or new process updates.
- Always was management's first choice to work on new scope added.
- Always maintained good rapport with all worldwide SSC.
- Daily production activities count (individual) dashboard.
- VAT, SST Tax Invoice creation for EMEA, ASIA, NAM regions.
- Preparation of monthly/quarterly Credit management dashboard for multiple geos andchannel, follow up for collection comments on the overdue aging.
- Immediate back up of manager in his absence for any point of query.
- Cross worked on Account Payable process as well as General Ledger process.
- Prepared Standard Operating Procedure (SOP) for all day-to-day activities.
- Created video trainings for new joiners to understand the processes better.
- Was responsible for preparing powerpoint presentations (PPT) for all the monthly meetings conducted in team where the team's performance, volumes processed, VOS, quality, appreciations, TAT, targets, expectations are presented.
- Was responsible for preparing minutes of meetings(MOM) for all the meetings conducted in team.

#### Month-end and Quarter-end reporting Activities:

- Bad debt reporting (V1 & V2).
- Booking accruals.
- AR to GL reconciliation activity.
- Maturity Reporting.
- Unbilled and deferred revenue calculation.
- Revenue reconciliation.
- Contract testing.
- Trial Balance.
- Withholding tax reconciliation for EMEA, ASIA, NAM, INDIA regions.

#### **Intercompany Invoicing:**

- Creation of STC numbers for Intercompany Business Units and update the details oftransactions.
- Update the STC transactions events on periodically basis and reconciliations.
- Amendment of STC numbers as per requirements and credit notes against incorrect transactions.

- Change the events of STC's manually and finalize the invoices for intercompanybusiness.
- Reconciliations of intercompany business transactions with events generated againstoperating units.

#### Financial Planning & Analysis (FP&A):

- Revenue Check to check the data consistency between 3DExperience and PA tool. Theactual quarter total revenue and Brand wise data is considered for checking the consistency.
- KPI check to check all the dashboards data and date status updated or not.
- OHR Hiring form are sent to respective owners on every Monday directly throughBusiness Objects.
- Revenue Modeling & Predictive Analysis ALC & YLC to check the actuals and baseline renewals by Brand, Geo and Industry. To assess or firm up the impacts of net churn, laterenewals, long period renewals, catch-ups, maintenance rates and other key assumptionimpacts on quarterly ALC revenue and predictive revenue over the next quarters.

#### **Sub. Role - Quality Auditor:**

- Individuals audit in team on daily basis.
- Performed quality check for entire team members.
- Preparation of standard operating procedures for process.
- Preparation of checklist of all activities for internal control and maintaining processupdates trackers.
- Arranging quarterly refreshers & brainstorming sessions.
- Monthly TAT and Quality % calculation and reports preparation.
- Feedback and coaching session on monthly basis.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Mahindra First Choice Rahul Auto Services Pvt Ltd Talegaon, Pune

#### Accountant

#### <u>Duration: March 2015 – September 2015</u>

- Purchase booking on SAP.
- Petty Cash booking on SAP.
- Credit Card bookings on SAP.
- Billing and Creation of tax invoices on SAP.

#### KEY MILESTONE

- Worked in internal VBA automation team (BAPS AUTOMATION TEAM).
- Streamlining the Billing for Indian Business units after the implementation of GST Tax.
- Awarded as Star of the month.
- Awarded as Highest number of idea shared for Improvements within brand.
- Received highest number of appreciations from Shared Service Center (Counterparts).
- Created own benchmark in multiple processes by achieving highest count.
- Awarded as CLUB 100 member for maintaining quality at 100% for continuous years.
- Participation in all Org level & Brand level activities Winner at Org level activity (SKITPerformance).
- FUNHOLIC team member for the fun activities conducted within team as well as inbrand level.
- Journalist in internal weekly magazine of Finance & SBA team called as Thank God It's Friday.
- Core committee member for WINspiration an Initiative for the Women, by the Womenand of the Women.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi, Marathi, Malayalam, French.

#### HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Drawing, Painting, Listening to Music, Travelling.

#### PERSONAL VITAE

Date of Birth : 29<sup>th</sup> April, 1992

Marital Status : Married

Permanent Residential Address : Flat No. 202, Bldg No. 4 (Compaq), Sector 4, Jasmine

CHS Mahalaxmi Nagar, Nere, Panvel, Navi

Mumbai, Maharashtra –410206.

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Marathi, Malayalam, French.

Gender : Female Nationality : Indian

Mobile Number : +91 9689680769

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above given information is true to the best of my knowledge & belief.

Place:

Date: / /2022

(Riya Kuriakose)